<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Matplotblog</title><link>https://matplotlib.org/matplotblog/categories/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Matplotblog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 21:47:36 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matplotlib.org/matplotblog/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sidharth Bansal joined as GSoC'20 intern</title><link>https://matplotlib.org/matplotblog/posts/introductory-gsoc2020-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 21:47:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://matplotlib.org/matplotblog/posts/introductory-gsoc2020-post/</guid><description>When I, Sidharth Bansal, heard I got selected in Google Summer of Code(GSOC) 2020 with Matplotlib under Numfocus, I was jumping and dancing. In this post, I talk about my past experiences, how I got selected for GSOC with Matplotlib, and my project details. I am grateful to the community :)
About me: I am currently pursuing a Bachelor’s in Technology in Software Engineering at Delhi Technological University, Delhi, India. I started my journey of open source with Public Lab, an open-source organization as a full-stack Ruby on Rails web developer.</description></item><item><title>Elliott Sales de Andrade hired as Matplotlib Software Research Engineering Fellow</title><link>https://matplotlib.org/matplotblog/posts/matplotlib-rsef/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 15:51:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://matplotlib.org/matplotblog/posts/matplotlib-rsef/</guid><description>As has been discussed in detail in Nadia Eghbal's Roads and Bridges, the CZI EOSS program announcement, and in the NumFocus sustainability program goals, much of the critical software that science and industry are built on is maintained by a primarily volunteer community. While this has worked, it is not sustainable in the long term for the health of many projects or their contributors.
We are happy to announce that we have hired Elliott Sales de Andrade (QuLogic) as the Matplotlib Software Research Engineering Fellow supported by the Chan Zuckerberg Initiative Essential Open Source Software for Science effective March 1, 2020!</description></item></channel></rss>